https://www.helenoftroy.com/privacy-policy/

Privacy Policy
HELEN OF TROY LIMITED – PRIVACY POLICY- 9/29/17
WE VALUE THE TRUST YOU PLACE IN HELEN OF TROY AND/OR ITS AFFILIATES (REFERRED TO AS “HELEN OF TROY” OR “WE” OR “OUR”). WE WANT TO ENSURE THAT YOU UNDERSTAND WHAT INFORMATION WE GATHER ABOUT YOU, HOW WE USE IT, AND THE SAFEGUARDS WE HAVE IN PLACE IN ORDER TO PROTECT IT. IF YOU HAVE ADDITIONAL QUESTIONS OR WOULD LIKE FURTHER INFORMATION ON THIS TOPIC, PLEASE FEEL FREE TO CONTACT US: 1-800-487-7273 OR RETAIL_CONSUMER_SERVICES@HOTUS.COM (MAILTO: RETAIL_CONSUMER_SERVICES@HOTUS.COM).
PLEASE READ THIS POLICY CAREFULLY TO UNDERSTAND OUR POLICIES AND PRACTICES REGARDING YOUR INFORMATION AND HOW WE WILL TREAT IT. BY ACCESSING OR USING THIS WEBSITE, YOU AGREE TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE WITH OUR POLICIES AND PRACTICES, YOUR CHOICE IS NOT TO USE OUR WEBSITE. HELEN OF TROY MAY UPDATE THIS POLICY FROM TIME TO TIME. PLEASE VISIT THIS PAGE PERIODICALLY TO REVIEW THE PRIVACY POLICY. YOUR CONTINUED USE OF THIS WEBSITE AFTER WE MAKE CHANGES IS DEEMED TO BE ACCEPTANCE OF THOSE CHANGES.
CHILDREN UNDER THE AGE OF 13
OUR WEBSITE IS NOT INTENDED FOR CHILDREN UNDER 13 YEARS OF AGE. NO ONE UNDER AGE 13 MAY PROVIDE ANY INFORMATION TO OR ON THE WEBSITE. WE DO NOT KNOWINGLY COLLECT PERSONAL INFORMATION FROM CHILDREN UNDER 13. IF YOU ARE UNDER 13, DO NOT USE OR PROVIDE ANY INFORMATION ON THIS WEBSITE OR ON OR THROUGH ANY OF ITS FEATURES, USE ANY OF THE INTERACTIVE OR PUBLIC COMMENT FEATURES OF THIS WEBSITE OR PROVIDE ANY INFORMATION ABOUT YOURSELF TO US, INCLUDING YOUR NAME, ADDRESS, TELEPHONE NUMBER, EMAIL ADDRESS, OR ANY SCREEN NAME OR USER NAME YOU MAY USE. IF WE LEARN WE HAVE COLLECTED OR RECEIVED PERSONAL INFORMATION FROM A CHILD UNDER 13 WITHOUT VERIFICATION OF PARENTAL CONSENT, WE WILL DELETE THAT INFORMATION. IF YOU BELIEVE WE MIGHT HAVE ANY INFORMATION FROM OR ABOUT A CHILD UNDER 13, PLEASE CONTACT US AT THE NUMBER LISTED ABOVE.
HOW DOES HELEN OF TROY ENSURE THAT YOUR INFORMATION IS SECURE?
HELEN OF TROY WILL MAINTAIN PRACTICES AND PROCEDURES DESIGNED TO ENSURE THE SECURITY, INTEGRITY AND CONFIDENTIALITY OF CUSTOMER INFORMATION. WE RESTRICT AND LIMIT ACCESS TO CUSTOMER INFORMATION ONLY TO THOSE OF OUR EMPLOYEES OR AUTHORIZED SERVICE PROVIDERS WHO NEED IT TO CARRY OUT THEIR BUSINESS FUNCTIONS, AND EDUCATE OUR EMPLOYEES ABOUT SAFEGUARDING CUSTOMER INFORMATION AND PREVENTING ITS UNAUTHORIZED ACCESS, DISCLOSURE, OR USE. WHEN CREDIT CARD INFORMATION IS TRANSMITTED ONLINE, HELEN OF TROY USES INDUSTRY STANDARD SECURITY MEASURES CALLED SSL (SECURE SOCKET LAYER ENCRYPTION). WHILE HELEN OF TROY CURRENTLY DOES NOT COLLECT PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION ABOUT AN INDIVIDUAL CONSUMER’S ONLINE ACTIVITIES OVER TIME AND ACROSS THIRD-PARTY WEB SITES OR ONLINE SERVICES, HELEN OF TROY ALSO DOES NOT RESPOND TO WEB BROWSER “DO NOT TRACK” SIGNALS OR OTHER MECHANISMS THAT PROVIDE CONSUMERS THE ABILITY TO EXERCISE CHOICE REGARDING THE COLLECTION OF PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION ABOUT AN INDIVIDUAL CONSUMER’S ONLINE ACTIVITIES OVER TIME AND ACROSS THIRD-PARTY WEB SITES OR ONLINE SERVICES.
WHAT TYPE OF INFORMATION DOES HELEN OF TROY COLLECT?
HELEN OF TROY GATHERS CUSTOMER INFORMATION NEEDED TO PROVIDE SUPERIOR SERVICE, COMMUNICATE OFFERS ON MERCHANDISE AND SERVICES THAT WE BELIEVE WILL BE OF INTEREST TO YOU, AND TO ADMINISTER OUR BUSINESS. IN ORDER TO BEST SERVE YOU, WE MAY GATHER INFORMATION FROM YOU IN A FEW INSTANCES. FIRST, WHEN YOU VISIT OUR SITE, WE MAY COLLECT NON-PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION FROM YOU. THROUGH THE USE OF COMPUTER “COOKIES” (SMALL PIECES OF INFORMATION THAT ARE STORED BY THE BROWSER ON YOUR HARD DRIVE), WE COLLECT DATA, SUCH AS YOUR IP ADDRESS, BROWSER TYPE, DOMAIN NAME, AND SPECIFIC HELEN OF TROY WEB PAGES THROUGH WHICH YOU CLICK. THE COOKIES THAT ARE CONFIGURED BY US DO NOT CONTAIN ANY PERSONALLY IDENTIFYING INFORMATION, SUCH AS YOUR NAME, OR SENSITIVE INFORMATION, SUCH AS YOUR CREDIT CARD NUMBER. THIS DATA IS COLLECTED AUTOMATICALLY, AND UTILIZED IN AGGREGATE TO HELP US LOOK FOR TRENDS SO THAT WE CAN IMPROVE OUR WEBSITE AND YOUR HELEN OF TROY EXPERIENCE. THE COOKIES ALSO ALLOW US TO RECOGNIZE YOU WHEN YOU RETURN TO OUR SITE AND TO PROVIDE YOU WITH A CUSTOMIZED EXPERIENCE THAT WE FEEL WILL BE OF VALUE TO YOU. MOST WEB BROWSERS ALLOW YOU TO EXERCISE CONTROL OVER COOKIE FILES ON YOUR COMPUTER BY ERASING THEM, BLOCKING THEM, OR NOTIFYING YOU WHEN SUCH A FILE IS STORED. PLEASE TAKE A LOOK AT YOUR PARTICULAR BROWSER FOR INSTRUCTIONS ON THIS FUNCTION. IF YOU DO ELECT TO DISABLE THE HELEN OF TROY COOKIE, PLEASE NOTE THAT YOU MAY NOT BE ABLE TO TAKE FULL ADVANTAGE OF A PERSONALIZED EXPERIENCE AT HELEN OF TROY. SECOND, WE MAY ASK YOU TO VOLUNTARILY PROVIDE INFORMATION IN A FEW CIRCUMSTANCES. WHEN YOU PURCHASE ITEMS, WE WILL ASK YOU TO VOLUNTARILY PROVIDE CERTAIN PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION, SUCH AS, YOUR NAME, ADDRESS, TELEPHONE NUMBER, E-MAIL ADDRESS, AND CREDIT CARD NUMBER. WE NEED THIS INFORMATION TO PROCESS AND FULFILL YOUR ORDER AND NOTIFY YOU OF ORDER STATUS. OTHER EXAMPLES OF WHEN WE MAY ASK YOU TO VOLUNTARILY PROVIDE PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION INCLUDE IF YOU SUBSCRIBE TO OUR EMAIL PROGRAM (INFORMATION SUCH AS YOUR NAME AND E-MAIL ADDRESS), CHOOSE TO PROVIDE US PREFERENCE INFORMATION (SUCH AS INTERESTS, PRODUCT PREFERENCES, AND ITEMS PURCHASED), OR WHEN YOU ENTER A SWEEPSTAKES OR PROMOTION (INFORMATION SUCH AS NAME, ADDRESS AND TELEPHONE NUMBER). ADDITIONALLY, IN ORDER TO PROVIDE YOU WITH GOODS AND SERVICES DESIGNED TO MEET YOUR NEEDS, WE MAY COLLECT DEMOGRAPHIC INFORMATION (SUCH AS NUMBER OF HOUSEHOLD MEMBERS, AGE, AND GENDER), PURCHASE PREFERENCE INFORMATION, AND
MAILING LISTS FROM THIRD PARTIES. WE USE THIS INFORMATION TO CUSTOMIZE YOUR EXPERIENCE ON OUR WEBSITE AND TO PROVIDE YOU WITH THE MOST RELEVANT PRODUCTS AND SERVICES.
HELEN OF TROY ALSO USES GOOGLE ANALYTICS AND ADWORDS TO COMPILE INFORMATION COLLECTED VIA COOKIES IN A MANNER WHICH IS HELPFUL TO US IN ANALYZING VISITORS’ USE OF THE SITE. GOOGLE ANALYTICS ALSO USES THIS INFORMATION TO PLACE ADVERTISEMENTS FOR OUR PRODUCTS ON OTHER SITES THAT YOU VISIT AFTER YOU VISIT OUR WEBSITE. THESE ADVERTISEMENTS MAY BE BASED ON THE PAGES YOU VISITED DURING YOUR USE OF OUR WEBSITE. THIS INFORMATION MAY BE SHARED WITH OTHER ORGANIZATIONS SUCH AS ADVERTISERS AND OUR PARTNERS, WHO MIGHT USE IT WITH INFORMATION ABOUT HOW YOU USE OTHER WEBSITES, INCLUDING TO IDENTIFY SHARED INTERESTS AND BEHAVIORS ACROSS GROUPS OF USERS WHO VISIT OUR (AND OTHER) WEBSITE. TO LEARN MORE, VISIT “HOW GOOGLE USES DATA WHEN YOU USE OUR PARTNER SITES OR APPS.” USERS MAY OPT OUT OF GOOGLE’S USE OF COOKIES BY VISITING GOOGLE ANALYTICS OPT-OUT BROWSER ADD-ON. USERS MAY OPT OUT OF THIRD PARTY VENDOR USE OF THE COOKIES BY VISITING THE NETWORK ADVERTISING INITIATIVE OPT-OUT PAGE.
WHAT INFORMATION DO WE SHARE AND WITH WHOM?
HELEN OF TROY DOES NOT RENT OR SELL CUSTOMER INFORMATION TO OUTSIDE MARKETERS. IN CERTAIN CIRCUMSTANCES, HELEN OF TROY MAY SHARE YOUR CUSTOMER INFORMATION WITH OUR SUBSIDIARIES OR AFFILIATES OR TRUSTED SERVICE PROVIDERS THAT NEED ACCESS TO YOUR INFORMATION TO PROVIDE OPERATIONAL OR OTHER SUPPORT SERVICES. TO ENSURE THE CONFIDENTIALITY AND SECURITY OF YOUR INFORMATION, SERVICE PROVIDERS MUST AGREE TO SAFEGUARD YOUR INFORMATION IN STRICT COMPLIANCE WITH OUR POLICY. WE ALSO MAY PROVIDE INFORMATION TO REGULATORY AUTHORITIES AND LAW ENFORCEMENT OFFICIALS IN ACCORDANCE WITH APPLICABLE LAW OR WHEN WE OTHERWISE BELIEVE IN GOOD FAITH THAT THE LAW REQUIRES IT. IN THE EVENT OF A SALE OF ALL OR PART OF ONE OF OUR BUSINESSES, WE MAY SHARE CUSTOMER INFORMATION RELATED TO THAT BUSINESS AS PART OF THE TRANSACTION.
HELEN OF TROY MAY DISCLOSE AGGREGATED INFORMATION ABOUT OUR USERS, AND INFORMATION THAT DOES NOT IDENTIFY ANY INDIVIDUAL, WITHOUT RESTRICTION.
CAN I “OPT OUT” OF RECEIVING PROMOTIONAL E-MAILS FROM HELEN OF TROY?
HELEN OF TROY MAY SEND YOU E-MAILS WITH PROMOTIONAL OFFERS. IF YOU WOULD NO LONGER LIKE TO RECEIVE E-MAILED SPECIAL EVENT INFORMATION, SALES NOTIFICATIONS OR OTHER MESSAGES FROM HELEN OF TROY, YOU MAY CONTACT US AT 1-800-487-7273 OR RETAIL_CONSUMER_SERVICES@HOTUS.COM (MAILTO:RETAIL_CONSUMER_SERVICES@HOTUS.COM) AND YOUR E-MAIL ADDRESS WILL BE REMOVED FROM OUR MARKETING LIST OR CLICK HERE TO FILL AN OPT OUT REQUEST FORM.
HOW CAN I ACCESS MY HELEN OF TROY INFORMATION OBTAINED THROUGH THIS WEBSITE?
YOU CAN ACCESS YOUR HELEN OF TROY INFORMATION OBTAINED THROUGH THIS WEBSITE BY CONTACTING US AT 1-800-487-7273 OR RETAIL_CONSUMER_SERVICES@HOTUS.COM OR CLICK HERE TO FILL AN INFORMATION REQUEST FORM.
ALL WEBSITE DESIGN, GRAPHICS, TEXT SELECTIONS ARRANGEMENT, AND SOFTWARE ARE COPYRIGHT 2017, HELEN OF TROY ALL RIGHTS RESERVED.
